Guide to the Rice University Early Land Deeds, Contracts and Related Records, 1830-1969 UA 222
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series II: Rice Institute Papers (Working Rice papers - including some deeds), 1891-1966; 144456; 29 Linear Feet
  - Campus Construction, 1910-1940; 144651; 5.3 Linear Feet
    - Contract with C. Culver, addition to field house (athletic offices), 1938, 144689 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Contracts - additions/extension of Rice Field (stadium), 1938-1940, 144680
      - Southwestern Construction Company, 1938, 144688 (Box 45, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
      - The Warren Company, plumbing, 1938, 144687 (Box 45, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - Ellis Electric Company, 1938, 144686 (Box 45, Folder 2, Subfolder 3)
      - Parker Brothers and Company, grading of parking lot, 1938-1939, 144685 (Box 45, Folder 2, Subfolder 4)
      - Mann Electric Company, night lighting of Rice Field, 1939-1940, 144684 (Box 45, Folder 2, Subfolder 5)
      - Contracts for fencing, folding gates, etc., 1938, 144683 (Box 45, Folder 2, Subfolder 6)
      - C.W. Ennis, press box, additional ramps, 1939, 144682 (Box 45, Folder 2, Subfolder 7)
      - William Ward Watkins, architectural fees, 1938-1939, 144681 (Box 45, Folder 2, Subfolder 8)
    - Contracts for construction of Rice buildings, 1931-1936, 144671
      - Don Hall, contract for alterations/additions to Field House, 1931, 144679 (Box 45, Folder 3, Subfolder 1)
      - Jacobe Brothers, Athletic Field House electrical work, 1931, 144678 (Box 45, Folder 3, Subfolder 2)
      - William Ward Watkins, architects fee, Athletic Field House additions, 1931, 144677 (Box 45, Folder 3, Subfolder 3)
      - William Ward Watkins, architects fee, steel grandstand, 1935, 144676 (Box 45, Folder 3, Subfolder 4)
      - E.A. Fretz, construction of steel grandstand, 1935, 144675 (Box 45, Folder 3, Subfolder 5)
      - E.A. Fretz, sidewalk construction under South grandstand, 1935, 144674 (Box 45, Folder 3, Subfolder 6)
      - Pete Nelson, Athletic Field House addition, dressing room, 1936, 144673 (Box 45, Folder 3, Subfolder 7)
      - George J. Robischung, Inc., Athletic Field House, plumbing and heating, 1931, 144672 (Box 45, Folder 3, Subfolder 8)
    - Contracts for construction of Rice buildings, 1929-1947, 144661
      - Various contracts, addition to Chemistry building, 1939, 144670 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 1)
      - Various contracts, dining hall extension, residence hall for men, 1939, 144669 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 2)
      - Otis Elevator Company, elevator in Administration building, 1937, 144668 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 3)
      - Dana E. Chase, Naval ROTC unit, 1941, 144667 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 4)
      - York Ice Machinery, refrigeration equipment in residence halls and Power house, 1929, 144666 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 5)
      - George Chambers, Firestone Sales and Service building, 1941, 144665 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 6)
      - E. Lee Bond, remodeling of drafting room, engineering annex, 1947, 144664 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 7)
      - Harry H. Hedges, topping roadways on campus, 1938, 144663 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 8)
      - Southwestern Construction Company, addition to Mechanical Lab, 1938, 144662 (Box 45, Folder 4, Subfolder 9)
    - President's House construction correspondence, 1913, 144660 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Physical laboratory building construction, correspondence, 1913, 144659 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Utility planning for dormitory #2, 1913-1919, 144658 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Blueprint specifications (Blueprints):, 144653
      - Administration building, 144657 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Mechanical building and Power House, 144656 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Residence hall for men, 144655 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Administration building, 145538 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Electric street lighting system, 144654 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Time rolls for campus construction projects (oversize), 144652 (Box 48)
  - Legal Matters and Papers, 144559
    - Settlements, 144646
      - Settlement with Mrs. John Gray, 1921, 144650 (Box 49, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Settlement with M.W. Forest, 1916, 144649 (Box 49, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
      - Settlement with J.B. Oliver, 1914, 144648 (Box 49, Folder 1, Subfolder 3)
      - Settlement in suit of Clyde L. Minthorn vs Rice Institute, 1939, 144647 (Box 49, Folder 1, Subfolder 4)
    - Copy of fraudulent will of William M. Rice, 1900 (1923), 144645 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Order of decree, estate of William M. Rice, 1901 (1916), 144644 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Various legal documents, 144626
      - Will of William Marsh Rice, 1896, 1929, 1939, 144643 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 1)
      - Agreement, estate of William M. Rice with William M. Rice, Jr., 1905, 144642 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 2)
      - Estate of William M. Rice, securities receipt and note, 1903, 144641 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 3)
      - Deed, William M. Rice and Elizabeth Baldwin Rice, to lands in Jones Co., 1892, 144640 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 4)
      - Deed, William M. Rice and Elizabeth Baldwin Rice, to 6 1/2 acres in Houston, Harris Co., 1892, 144639 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 5)
      - Deed, William M. Rice to land on Main St. and Congress, Harris Co., 1893, 144638 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 6)
      - Deed, William M. Rice to Rice Land Lumber Company, Louisiana lands and timber, 1911, 144637 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 7)
      - Decree copy, appointing H.B. Rice permanent administrator, 1901, 144636 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 8)
      - Letter from William M. Rice to A.B. Cohen, requesting deeds, 1899, 144635 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 9)
      - Original deeds from William M. Rice and Elizabeth Rice, conveying Rice Hotel property and other properties to Institute, 1892, 1900, 1910, 144634 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 10)
      - Contract between William M. Rice and H.B. Rice, 1892-1903, 144633 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 11)
      - Copy, deed of partition, 1905, 1911, 144632 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 12)
      - Will of Elizabeth B. Rice, 1902, 1910, 1918, 144631 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 13)
      - Copies, Rice Institute Charter and By-laws, 1941, 1946, undated, 144630 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 14)
      - David Rice affidavits, 1901-1902, 144629 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 15)
      - Report, disposition of amounts paid in settlements by William M. Rice Institute, 1904, 144628 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 16)
      - Correspondence concerning Rice Institute, 1916, 1918, 1926, 144627 (Box 49, Folder 4, Subfolder 17)
    - Agreements between Charlotte McKee, et al and Rice Institute, 1901, 144625 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Agreements between Charlotte McKee, et al and Rice Institute, 1901, 144624 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Guardianship papers and deeds, Nina Belle Rice, 1902, 144623 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Guardianship papers and deeds, Nina Belle Rice, 1902, 144622 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Releases from heirs of Elizabeth Baldwin Rice, 1911, 144621 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Judicial settlements, 144597
      - Jonas C. Baldwin & Mamie B. Huntington, 1902, 144620 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Annie Baldwin Brown & J. Sales Brown, 1902, 144619 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Bayland's Orphan Home, 1902, 144618 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Christ Church, Houston, 1902, 144617 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Estate of Walker Curry, 1906, 144616 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - DePelchin Faith Home Association, 1902, 144615 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Drawing Room Society of New York, 1905-1906, 144614 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - First Presbyterian Church of Houston, 1902, 144613 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Estate of Lillian E. Huntington, minor, 1902, 144612 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - Estate of Frederick Rice Lummis & Patty Hall Lummis, minors, 1903, 144611 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Parish Aid Society. Christ Church Houston, 1902, 144610 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Estate of Elizabeth B. Rice, 1902, 144609 (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - Estate of Libbie R., H. Baldwin, Brown Botts & Fred A. Rice, minors, 1902, 144608 (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - Estate of R. Rutherford, 1902, 144607 (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Eric P. Swenson, S. Alvin Swenson, S.M. Swenson & Sons, Harry Zeamen, 1904-1905, 144606 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - Bessie Campbell & James H. Trezevant, 1902, 144605 (Box 51, Folder 16)
      - Walter O. Wetherbe, 1905, 144604 (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - Charles W. Rice, 1902, 144603 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Benjamin Franklin Rice, 1902, 144602 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Olds, McKee, et al, 1904, 144601 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Benjamin Franklin Rice, Walter Scott Rice, Charlotte Rice Clark, et al, 1901-1902, 144600 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - William A. Rice, Charles W. Rice, Benjamin F. Rice, et al, 1902, 144599 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Jonas S. Rice, William N. Rice, Charlotte M. Rice, et al, 1902, 144598 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Judicial statements, 144577
      - Adam T. Baldwin, 1902, 144596 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Adele M. Baldwin, 1907, 1910, 144595 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Elizabeth Baldwin, home, 1902, 144594 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Frank T. Baldwin, 1902, 144593 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - Sarah Baldwin, 1902, 144592 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Stephen W. Baldwin, 1902, 144591 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Bettie B. Brown, 1902, 144590 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Diet Kitchen Society of New York City, 1907, 144589 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - J. Isabelle Dorwin, 1902, 144588 (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - Calriot H. & Edgar L. Heriot, 1902, 144587 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Estate of Minerva R. Olds, 1908, 144586 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Willieta & Charles E. Parker, et al, 1910, 144585 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Belle Wallace & Sidney B. Perkins, 1907, 144584 (Box 53, Folder 13)
      - Estate of William M. Rice to Rice Institute, 1907, 144583 (Box 53, Folder 14)
      - Julia Roberts, 1907, 144582 (Box 53, Folder 15)
      - Marian Roberts Robinson & Beverly Robinson, 1907, 144581 (Box 53, Folder 16)
      - Lola Martin & Daniel E. Seybel, 1907, 144580 (Box 53, Folder 17)
      - Mary S. & Mary E. Turnure, 1907, 144579 (Box 53, Folder 18)
      - Annie G. Lippincott - Winslow & H.H. Winslow, 1902, 144578 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Estate of Elizabeth B. Rice vs William M. Rice, Eastern District, Galveston, 1903, 144576 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Estate of Elizabeth B. Rice vs William M. Rice, Western District, Austin, 1898-1901, 144575 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Estate of Elizabeth B. Rice vs William M. Rice, Eastern District, Waller Co., 1903, 144574 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Bill of Complaint, William M. Rice vs Orren Holt, Executor for the Estate of Elizabeth B. Rice, 1898, 144573 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Lawsuit: Estate of Elizabeth B. Rice vs Rice Institute (Rice Hotel property), 1904, 144572 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Bonds owned by estate of William M. Rice, 1907, 144571 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - List of securities owned by the estate of William M. Rice, 1906, 144570 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Inventory of paintings presented to Rice Institute by William M. Rice, 1909, 144569 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Final Decree: Estate of William M. Rice vs Estate of Elizabeth B. Rice, 1903, 144568 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - List of assets of Rice Institute received from William M. Rice, 1906, 144567 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Final summary of the estate of William M. Rice, presented to Rice Institute by executors, 1906, 144566 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence concerning the prosecution of Short & Meyers, 1910, 144565 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Testimony of Emmanuel Raphael, 1902, 144564 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence concerning Rice vs Patrick, litigation records, 1931, 144563 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and bank statements concerning refund of legacy taxes to the estate of William Marsh Rice, 1929, 144562 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Dismissed suit, H.M. Hamilton vs Rice Institute re: Rice Hotel renovations, 1909, 144561 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Edward Rice vs Estate of William Marsh Rice, 1919, 144560 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Institutional Housekeeping, 144509
    - Rice Institute lands, Harris Co., 1906-1909, 144558 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Checkbook and cancelled checks, Rice Institute, 1894-1902, 144557 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Receipts concerning death of Fred A. Rice, 1902, 144556 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Contracts, correspondence, receipts concerning renovation of Rice Hotel, 1900, 144555 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Invoices, receipts, correspondence, claims, disbursements covering trips to New York and Massachusetts for lawsuits, 1900-1907, 144554 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Hohenthal Fund, 144550
      - Stock shares, The Revenue Leasing and Mining Company, 1900-1908, 144553 (Box 55, Folder 6, Subfolder 1)
      - Galena-Signal Oil Company, 1917-1934, 144552 (Box 55, Folder 6, Subfolder 2)
      - Other stocks, 1895-1923, 1930, 1945, 144551 (Box 55, Folder 6, Subfolder 3)
    - William Marsh Rice Institute, receipt book, 1894-1896, 144549 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1891-1899, 144548 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1900, 144547 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1901, 144545
      - Jones County lawsuit expenses, 1901, 144546 (Box 56, Folder 4, Subfolder 1)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1902, 144544 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1903, 144543 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1904, 144542 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1905, 144541 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1906, 144540 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Receipts and invoices, balance sheets, 1907, 144539 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Inventory and appraisal: Assets of Rice Institute, 1907, 144538 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Balance sheets and statements, 1908, 144537 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence concerning insurance for Rice Institute buildings, 1920, 144536 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Explosion insurance, 1929-1932, 144535 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Reciprocal, Mutual and Lloyd's America Insurance, 1930-1935, 144531
      - Reciprocal insurance, 1931, 144534 (Box 57, Folder 6, Subfolder 1)
      - Mutual insurance, 1930-1935, 144533 (Box 57, Folder 6, Subfolder 2)
      - Lloyd's American insurance, 1931-1932, 144532 (Box 57, Folder 6, Subfolder 3)
    - Correspondence, reports, policies, etc. concerning Rice Institute insurance, 1924-1942, 144530 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Various insurance coverages, 1915-1937, 144524
      - Employers' compensation insurance, 1925, 144529 (Box 58, Folder 2, Subfolder 1)
      - Explosion insurance, 1935, 144528 (Box 58, Folder 2, Subfolder 2)
      - Schedule of burglary and robbery insurance, undated, 144527 (Box 58, Folder 2, Subfolder 3)
      - Purchase of war bonds, 1917, 144526 (Box 58, Folder 2, Subfolder 4)
      - Bonds for various employees, 1936-1937, 144525 (Box 58, Folder 2, Subfolder 5)
    - Fire insurance coverage, 1916-1918, 144523 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Insurance, 1907-1936, 144516
      - Liability insurance, 1914-1916, 144522 (Box 58, Folder 4, Subfolder 1)
      - Insurance research, 1936, 144521 (Box 58, Folder 4, Subfolder 2)
      - Removing fire extinguishers from residence halls, 1929-1930, 144520 (Box 58, Folder 4, Subfolder 3)
      - Bonds, A.B. Cohen, J.A. Flick, W.M. Reynolds, 1907-1932, 144519 (Box 58, Folder 4, Subfolder 4)
      - Fire insurance cancellation, 1928, 144518 (Box 58, Folder 4, Subfolder 5)
      - Fire insurance, Rice and Eagleston, 1932, 144517 (Box 58, Folder 4, Subfolder 6)
    - Boiler inspections for insurance, 1914-1939, 144515 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Equipment inspections for insurance, 1914-1939, 144510
      - Elevator inspections, 1914-1916, 144514 (Box 58, Folder 6, Subfolder 1)
      - Engine inspections, 1926-1938, 144513 (Box 58, Folder 6, Subfolder 2)
      - Refrigeration inspections, 1927-1939, 144512 (Box 58, Folder 6, Subfolder 3)
      - Various equipment inspections, 1926-1930, 144511 (Box 58, Folder 6, Subfolder 4)
  - Campus Area Property, 144488
    - Tract disputes, Reinerman Survey (includes Brickworks), Harris County, 1906-1933, 144508 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Rice Institute lands, Harris County, 1906-1909, 144507 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Rice Hotel property purchase, 1898-1901, 144506 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - For sale and purchased, 144499
      - Sale, Capt. J.A. Baker Homestead Property, SSBB to M.D. Anderson Foundation, Harris County, 1942, 144505 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Sale, 14 lots SSBB (1914 Institute grounds) to City of Houston, Harris County, 1914-1928, 144504 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Tract Purchases, Harris County, 144500
        - Lot 7 in D.H. Paige Subdivision from Randon Poter, Harris County, 1922-1923, 144503 (Box 59, Folder 6, Subfolder 1)
        - Suit, Hardcastle vs. Rice Institute for 72 acres in Johnathan Austin Survey, Harris County, 1890, 1911-1913, 144502 (Box 59, Folder 6, Subfolder 2)
        - Re-opening of Camp Logan Golf Course for public use, correspondence, 1923, 144501 (Box 59, Folder 6, Subfolder 3)
    - Leases, 144492
      - Tract leases and exchanges out of Reinerman Survey, 1908-1937, 144495
        - 115 acre lease in J. Reinerman Survey, 1919-1923, 144498 (Box 60, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
        - Exchanges of land with Harris County for road purposes, 1918, 1937, 144497 (Box 60, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
        - Various leases out of J. Reinerman Survey, Harris County, 1908-1926, 144496 (Box 60, Folder 1, Subfolder 3)
      - Lease, parking lot at Rice Institute, SSBB to Durrell Carothers, Harris County, 1938, 144494 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Abstract of title and legal proceedings to Southampton Place, Harris County, 1923, 144493 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Deeds, 144489
      - Deeds and title to various Rice lands, 1892-1911, 144491 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - 8 acres in Obedience Smith Survey, Harris County (Rice Hotel property), 1902, 144490 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Campus Area Construction, 144457
    - O. Smith Survey, railroad spur, Rice Institute, Harris County, 1908-1924, 144487 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Receipts - contract with W. Waldo for construction of railroad spur, 1913, 144486 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Property for construction of Rice Blvd., Gamble and Rose Surveys, Harris County, 1923, 144485 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Property for construction of Sunset Rd., Gamble Survey, Harris County, 1918, 144484 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence concerning installation of water mains and lighting system, Shady Side Addition, Harris County, 1920, 144483 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Railroad spur, Reinerman St., Gamble Survey, Harris County, 1923-1926, 144482 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Right-of-way, Main St. widening project, City of Houston, Harris County, 1914, 144481 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and maps concerning Harris Bayou/Reynolds drainage through campus, 1923-1924, 144480 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Paving of Sunset Rd., Harris County, 1924-1928, 144479 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Sunset Rd., Shady Side Addition, Harris County, 1917-1920, 144478 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Sunset Rd. and Rice Blvd alignment, Harris County, 1918, 1923, 1950-1952, 144477 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Rice Blvd: Correspondence, copies of deeds of dedication, maps, 1923-1929, 144476 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - City water mains and fire hydrants into Rice Institute campus, 1924-1928, 144475 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Easement to City of Houston for right-of-way through Rice Institute campus for storm sewer, 1923-1928, 1941-1944, 144474 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Repaving Main St., 1940, 144473 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - L.R. Ashmore filling station, 6511 Main St., 1939, 144472 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Easement for storm sewer, South side of Sunset Rd., 1949, 144471 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Easement for extension of water mains through campus, 1931, 1956, 1967, 144470 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Greenbriar Dr., drainage and paving, 1930-1931, 1941, 144469 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Development of University Blvd.: Paving, walks, tree planting, 1929-1932, 144468 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Easement of sanitary sewer adjacent to Greenbriar and University Blvd., 1950, 144467 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Sanitary sewer easement, University and Greenbriar, 1950, 1956, 144466 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Dupont 10 acre tract purchase for fraternity house addition, 1912-1921, 144465 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Exchange of property with the City of Houston, 1916-1944, 144462
      - Correspondence, contracts, printed material concerning construction of retaining wall abutting Rice Institute property, 1925-1927, 144464 (Box 64, Folder 1, Subfolder 1)
      - Street improvements - Smith, Clay, Milam & Capitol, 1916-1928, 144463 (Box 64, Folder 1, Subfolder 2)
    - Papers concerning construction and lease of Brazos Valley Buick Co. building, Houston, 1916, 1927-1928, 144461 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - City of Houston construction on Rice property, 1908-1931, 144458
      - Sidewalk construction on Capitol Ave., 1931, 144460 (Box 64, Folder 3, Subfolder 1)
      - Abstracts, 1908-1917, 144459 (Box 64, Folder 3, Subfolder 2)
- Series III: Oversize drawers, 144192 (Drawer 129-131)
  - Blueprints (3) - plats showing Rice Institute lands occupied by Walter Cloud, 1907 (from box 1 folder 7), 144455 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Map showing proposed fence (from box 1, folder 9, sub-folder 3), 144450 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Map - right-of-way for Tennessee Gas Transmission Company, 1950 (from box 1, folder 9, sub-folder 7), 144449 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Plat showing right of way (from box 2, folder 2), 144446 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - sketch showing location of 160 acres asked for by school board for new Merryville school, 1917 (from box 2, folder 3), 144443 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Plat showing possible right of ways, 1921 (from box 2, folder 5), 144441 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - plat showing land sold to Louisiana Highway Commission in Beauregard Parish, 1928 (from box 2, folder 6), 144440 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint - plat showing exceptions in conveyance of land for Merryville school, 1918 (from box 2, folder 3), 144442 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Plat showing R/N fence encroachments, 1965; Blueprint Pro. trackage (from box 2, folder 10, sub-folder 3), 144431 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (2) - meter station site for Merryville, Louisiana, 1931 (from box 2, folder 7), 144438 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint, Neale to Atreco line, Beauregard Parish, 1942 (from box 2, folder 9), 144436 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (2) - 3" transmission lines to DeRidder La., 1935 Sheets 3 & 4 of 8 (from box 2, folder 10, sub-folder 4), 144430 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint showing area of general permit (from box 2, folder 10, sub-folder 5), 144429 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Map - Exhibit "A" of land leased to C.H. Watson (from box 3, folder 1, sub-folder 1), 144428 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprints (3) for Kinder & Northwestern right of way; Total footage taken by right of way; showing right of way through Rice lands, 1910 (from box 3, folder 3, sub-folder 6), 144425 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Blueprint showing right of way for Sabine Tram Co., 1910 (from box 3, folder 3, sub-folder 8), 144424 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - 21 certificates & patents for land held in Louisiana, 1884-1891 (from box 3, folder 3, sub-folder 12), 144423 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - List of town notes (from box 5, folder 1), 144420 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Plats (3) - showing location of transmission lines, sheets 1-3 (from box 2, folder 7), 144439 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 1)
  - Patent abstract #617, May 10, 1841 (from box 9, folder 17), 144407 (Map-drawer 129, Folder 2)